<resources>
    <string name="app_name">LazyColumn_And_RadioButton_Gallery</string>
    <string name="aivazovski">Aivazovski</string>
    <string name="salvador">Salvadot Dali</string>
    <string name="vanGogh">Van Gogh</string>
    <string name="klodMone">Claude Monet</string>
    <string name="picaso">Pablo Picaso</string>
    <string name="michelangelo">Michelangelo Buonarroti</string>
    <string name="sandroBotticelli">Sandro Botticelli</string>
    <string name="davinci">Leonardo Da Vinci</string>
    <string name="warholeAndy">ANDY WARHOLE</string>

    <string name="klod_mone">
        Oscar-Claude Monet  14 November 1840 – 5 December 1926)
        was a French painter and founder of impressionist painting who is seen as a key precursor to
        modernism, especially in his attempts to paint nature as he perceived it. During his long
        career, he was the most consistent and prolific practitioner of impressionism philosophy of
        expressing one\'s perceptions before nature, especially as applied to plain air (outdoor) landscape painting.
        The term \"Impressionism\" is derived from the title of his painting Impression, solely levant, exhibited in the 1874
        (\"exhibition of rejects\") initiated by Monet and his associates as an alternative to the Salon.
    </string>
    <string name="warhole_Andy">
      Andy Warhol was a successful magazine and ad illustrator who became a leading artist of the 1960s
        Pop art movements. He ventured into a wide variety of art forms, including performance art, filmmaking,
        video installations and writing and controversially blurred the lines between fine art and mainstream aesthetics
        . Warhol died on February 22, 1987, in New York City.
    </string>
    <string name="michelangelo_Buonarroti">
        Michelangelo di Lodovico Buoyant Simon ;
        6 March 1475 – 18 February 1564, known simply as Michelangelo , was
        an Italian sculptor, painter, architect and poet of the High Renaissance. Born in the Republic of Florence,
        his work had a major influence on the development of Western art, particularly in relation to the Renaissance
        notions of humanism and naturalism. He is often considered a contender for the title of the archetypal Renaissance man,
        along with his rival and elder contemporary, Leonardo da Vinci. Given the sheer volume of surviving correspondence,
        sketches, and reminiscences, Michelangelo is one of the best-documented artists of the 16th century and several scholars
        have described Michelangelo as the most accomplished artist of his era.
    </string>
    <string name="Sandro_Botticelli">
        Botticelli\’s name is derived from that of his elder brother Giovanni, a pawnbroker who was called
    Botticelli (Little Barrel). As is often the case with Renaissance artists, most of the modern information
    about Botticellis life and character derives from Giorgio Vassar Lives of the Most Eminent Painters, Sculptors,
    Architects, as supplemented and corrected from documents. Botticelli father was a tanner who apprenticed Sandro to
    a goldsmith after his schooling was finished. But, since Sandro preferred painting, his father then placed him under
    Filippo Lippi, who was one of the most admired Florentine masters.
    </string>
    <string name="aivazovski_desc">
        Ivan Konstantinovich Aivazovsky ( 29 July 1817 – 2 May 1900)
        was a Russian Romantic painter who is considered one of the greatest masters of marine art.
        Baptized as Hovhannes Aivazian, he was born into an Armenian family in the Black Sea port of
        Feodosia in Crimea and was mostly based there.
        Following his education at the Imperial Academy of Arts in Saint Petersburg, Aivazovsky traveled to Europe
        and lived briefly in Italy in the early 1840s. He then returned to Russia and was appointed the main
        painter of the Russian Navy. Aivazovsky had close ties with the military and political elite of the
        Russian Empire and often attended military maneuvers. He was sponsored by the state and was well-regarded
        during his lifetime. The saying \"worthy of Aivazovsky\'s brush\", popularized by Anton Chekhov, was used in
        Russia for describing something lovely. He remains highly popular in Russia in the 21st century
        </string>

    <string name="salvador_dali">
     Salvador Domingo Felipe Jacinto Dalí i Domènech, Marquess of Dalí of Púbol gcYC
          11 May 1904 – 23 January 1989) was
        a Spanish surrealist artist renowned for his technical skill, precise draftsmanship, and the striking
        and bizarre images in his work.
        Born in Figueres, Catalonia, Spain, Dalí received his formal education in fine arts in Madrid.
        Influenced by Impressionism and the Renaissance masters from a young age he became increasingly
        attracted to Cubism and avant-garde movements. He moved closer to Surrealism in the late 1920s
        and joined the Surrealist group in 1929, soon becoming one of its leading exponents. His best-known work,
        The Persistence of Memory, was completed in August 1931, and is one of the most famous Surrealist paintings
</string>
    <string name="van_gogh">
        Vincent van Gogh, in full Vincent Willem van Gogh, (born March 30, 1853, Zundert, Netherlands—died July 29,
        1890, Auvers-sur-Oise, near Paris, France), Dutch painter, generally considered the greatest
        after Rembrandt van Rijn, and one of the greatest of the Post-Impressionists. The striking colour,
        emphatic brushwork, and contoured forms of his work powerfully influenced the current of Expressionism in modern art.
    </string>
    <string name="pablo_picasso">
        Pablo Picasso was one of the greatest artists of the 20th century, famous for paintings like
        Guernica’ and for the art movement known as Cubism.
        Pablo Picasso was a Spanish painter, sculptor, printmaker, ceramicist and stage designer considered
        one of the greatest and most influential artists of the 20th century. Picasso is credited, along with
        Georges Braque, with the creation of Cubism.
        Pablo Picasso was born in Málaga, Spain, on October 25, 1881  His father was Don José Ruiz Blasco, a painter and art teacher.
        His gargantuan full name, which honors a variety of relatives and saints, is Pablo Diego José
        Francisco de Paula Juan Nepomuceno María de los Remedios Cipriano de la Santísima Trinidad Martyr Patricio Clito Ruíz y Picasso.
    </string>
    <string name="leonardo_da_vinci">
   Leonardo di ser Piero da Vinci (15 April 1452 – 2 May 1519) was an Italian polymath of the High
        Renaissance who was active as a painter, draughtsman, engineer, scientist, theorist, sculptor,
        and architect. While his fame initially rested on his achievements as a painter, he also became
        known for his notebooks, in which he made drawings and notes on a variety of subjects, including
        anatomy, astronomy, botany, cartography, painting, and paleontology. Leonardo is widely regarded to
        have been a genius who epitomized the Renaissance humanist ideal, and his collective works compose
        a contribution to later generations of artists matched only by that of his younger contemporary, Michelangelo.
</string>
</resources>